servsafe.com 2019-01-05

# ServSafe® - Privacy Policy

### Privacy Statement

National Restaurant Association Solutions LLC (“NRA Solutions”) respects your privacy and knows that you care about how your information is used or shared. We value your trust and have created this privacy statement so that you are aware of our commitment to maintaining it. By visiting or using our website, you consent to the information collection and use practices described in this Statement.

**Information Collected by NRA Solutions**

_Website Visitors.  _ If you are merely browsing an NRA Solutions website, the only information we collect about you is done in a way that preserves your anonymity. This NRA Solutions website logs the IP address and domain name used in connecting to the site to track a user's session for systems administration purposes only. We collect this information in order to assess which parts of our site users are visiting. We do not link IP addresses or domain names to anything personally identifiable. This means that a user's session will be tracked, but the user will be anonymous.

_Registered Users_.  You must register on this NRA Solutions’ website in order to purchase products, take online courses, sign up for email news, or engage in any other activity that requires us to keep track of your records individually. You can elect not to provide certain information, but then you may not be able to take advantage of our services without disclosure of this information.

_Payment Card Information._ If you make purchases on our website, we will collect payment card numbers and related information, such as the expiration date of the card. We will use this information only as needed for purposes of processing and completing the purchase transaction. Payment card information will be disclosed to third parties only as necessary to complete the purchase transaction.

_Voluntary Information._ On occasion, NRA Solutions may also survey and solicit feedback from users to help improve the products, services, and information that we provide. In the surveys, we may ask users to provide various information, which may include their name, email address, street address, zip code, telephone numbers, birth date, gender, salary range, education level, industry training, certifications, marital status, occupation, employment information, personal and online interests, and such other information as may be requested from time to time. These information requests are strictly voluntary. Such surveys may also provide you with opportunities to receive products or additional business-related information, but you may opt-out of receiving these communications at that time.

**Information Collected by NRA Solutions**

_Website Visitors.  _ If you are merely browsing an NRA Solutions website, the only information we collect about you is done in a way that preserves your anonymity. This NRA Solutions website logs the IP address and domain name used in connecting to the site to track a user's session for systems administration purposes only. We collect this information in order to assess which parts of our site users are visiting. We do not link IP addresses or domain names to anything personally identifiable. This means that a user's session will be tracked, but the user will be anonymous.

**Use of Personal Information**

_NRA Solutions'   Use of Your Personal Information_

We use your personal information to:

  * Fulfill your orders for products or services and for related activities, such as product and service delivery, customer service, account management, support and training and to provide other services related to your account;
  * Provide  you with marketing communications and offers for products and services from us and, in some cases, our partners, including offers targeted based on your interests, business characteristics and location;
  * Administer surveys and other promotional events;
  * Determine if you are eligible for certain products, services or offers;
  * Provide you with additional information that may be of interest, such as news and announcements and technical service bulletins; and
  * Manage our everyday business needs, such as payment processing and financial account management, product development, contract management, website administration, forum management, fulfillment, analytics, security and fraud prevention, corporate governance, reporting and legal compliance.

_NRA Solutions' Use of Your Personal Information._

We use your personal information to:

  * Fulfill _Sharing Your Personal Information_.  Other than as set forth below, we will not provide your personal information to unaffiliated third parties for their own use. We may share such information with our affiliates, the National Restaurant Association (“the Association”) and the National Restaurant Association Educational Foundation (“NRAEF”), and with our state restaurant association partners, who use it for financial account management, product development, fulfillment, analytics, corporate governance, reporting, marketing communications and offers for membership, products, and services.  NRA Solutions is not responsible for use of the shared information by any of these other entities. NRA Solutions may also share certain information with its examination proctors and instructors and state health departments for purposes of providing purchased services and verifying your identity only. If your access to goods or services on this NRA Solutions website has been paid for by another organization (e.g. your employer), NRA Solutions may also share information with that organization.

We may also disclose personal information where needed to effect the sale or transfer of business assets, to enforce our rights, protect our property, or protect the rights, property or safety of others, or as needed to support external auditing, compliance and corporate governance functions. We will also always disclose personal information when required to do so by law, such as in response to a subpoena, including to law enforcement agencies and courts in the United States and other countries where we operate.

We may also share your personal information with our service providers, who are bound by law or contract to protect your personal information and only use your personal information in accordance with our instructions. We may share your personal information with marketing agencies that are contracted on our behalf and business partners, but only to promote NRA Solutions, NRAEF, and Association products and services and Association approved, endorsed products and services.

We may share your Personal Information with our joint marketing partners and other carefully selected business partners who offer products and services to the hospitality and foodservice industry, so that these companies can offer you products and services that may be of interest to you.  For example, our business partners can provide NRAS members with discounts on healthcare, financial services, marketing services, technology, training, or  insurance products and services.   If you do not wish to receive offers from our business partners, please log into ServSafe.com, access the **Update Profile** page, and un-select “Receive Special Offer Emails” option under the Email Preferences section. You may also contact NRA Solutions via email at [servicecenter@restaurant.org](mailto:servicecenter@restaurant.org?subject=Request%20to%20opt%20out%20of%20emails) with a specific request to opt out of emails.

Finally, please note that we may also use and disclose information about you that is not personally identifiable. For example, we may publish reports that contain aggregated and statistical data about our customers. These reports do not contain any information that would enable the recipient to contact, locate or identify you. These reports also do not contain any identifiable company information.

_Access to Your Information_.  You may review and update the information we collect from you and maintain in our database by logging in to www.servsafe.com and clicking on **My Account**. We will remove information from our customer database or change/correct personal information upon your request. If you have any questions about changing your personal information, please contact us at [servicecenter@restaurant.org](mailto:servicecenter@restaurant.org?subject=Assistance%20with%20opting-out%20of%20emails).

_Your Choices_. You can always limit the information you provide to us. You can also limit the communications that we send to you. To opt-out of all emails, log into ServSafe.com, access the **Update Profile** page, and un-select “Receive Special Offer Emails” option under the Email Preferences section. You may also contact NRA Solutions via email at servicecenter@restaurant.org with a specific request to opt out of emails. Other than for e-mails specifically related to your account or purchases, all emails will allow you to click the link labeled “unsubscribe” at the bottom the email; however this will only opt you out of the current email campaign that may be occurring at that time and will not unsubscribe you from all emails.  

  Please note that even if you opt-out of promotional emails, we may still need to contact you with important transactional information about your account. For example, even if you opt-out of emails, we may still send you activity confirmations, account statements, or process and procedure updates related to programs in which you are enrolled.

  If you have any questions about your choices or if you need any assistance with opting-out, please contact us via email at [servicecenter@restaurant.org](mailto:servicecenter@restaurant.org?subject=Assistance%20with%20opting-out%20of%20emails).

**Public Forums**

This website may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, listservs and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information you disclose in these interactive areas, including your name, contact information and opinions expressed, may become public information. You should exercise caution when deciding what information to disclose in such areas of this website.

**Children**

_No Information Collected from Children_. This NRA Solutions website does not target children. We will never knowingly or intentionally collect any personal information about children under the age of 13. If we obtain actual knowledge that we have collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.

**Mobile Applications**

NRA Solutions offers mobile applications that allow you to enhance your learning with our products, access your account, interact with us online and receive other information via your smartphone.  All personal information collected by NRA Solutions via our mobile applications is protected by the terms of this Privacy Statement.

  We may also offer automatic (or "push") notifications. We will provide push notifications only to those customers who opt-in to receive such notifications from NRA Solutions. You do not have to enable push notifications to use any of our mobile apps. If you have questions about notification privacy, please contact your mobile service provider or the manufacturer of your device to learn how to adjust your settings.

**Security of Information**

We have implemented an information security program that contains administrative, technical and physical controls that are reasonably designed to safeguard your personal information at all times. For example, we use industry standard SSL encryption when accepting your payment card information during our processing of online forms. SSL encryption is a method by which information transmitted across the Internet is scrambled to the point where it is virtually indecipherable by anyone who should intercept the information before it reaches its destination. Most reputable online stores make use of SSL encryption to request credit card information and other sensitive information from their customers. A lock or key symbol displayed somewhere in your browser typically identifies web pages where SSL encryption is activated.

**Links to Other Sites**

This NRA Solutions website contains links to other websites, such as those belonging to our sponsors. While we expect the operators of such sites to handle your personal information in a manner that respects your privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this NRA Solutions website, servsafe.com. We encourage you to review the privacy of websites you choose to visit via links posted on this website so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information.

**Privacy Statement Modification**

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Statement to reflect new or different privacy practices. We will place a notice online when we make material changes to this Privacy Statement. Additionally, if the changes will materially affect the way we use or disclose previously collected personal information, we will notify you about the change by sending a notice to the primary email address associated with your account. The current version of this Statement is effective beginning April 2, 2012.

**Contact Us**

Website Privacy Inquiries  
Marketing Department  
National Restaurant Association Solutions  
233 S. Wacker Drive, Suite 3600  
Chicago, IL 60606-6383

Disclaimer

© 2008-2012 National Restaurant Association Educational Foundation. All rights reserved.

ServSafe is a registered trademark of the National Restaurant Association Educational Foundation (“NRAEF”), and used under license by National Restaurant Association Solutions, LLC (“NRA Solutions”) a wholly owned subsidiary of the National Restaurant Association (the “Association”). All materials posted on this website are subject to copyrights owned by the NRAEF, the Association, and/or NRA Solutions and/or other individuals or entities. Nothing on this website, including the names, trademarks, service marks and logos of the NRAEF, NRA Solutions, the Association, and/or other individuals or entities may be reproduced, stored in a retrieval system, modified, made available on a network, used to create derivative works, or transmitted in any form or by any means electronic, mechanical, photocopying, recording, scanning, or otherwise except (1) as permitted under Sections 107 and 108 of the 1976 United States Copyright Act, or (2) as expressly authorized on this website, or (3) without prior written permission of the NRAEF, NRA Solutions, the Association, and/or individuals or entities, as appropriate. No permission is granted herein to use __NRA Solutions’__ icons, site address, or other means to link other websites with any page in this website.

Requests to use or reproduce material from this website should be directed to:

**Copyright Permissions**  
National Restaurant Association Educational Foundation  
233 S. Wacker Drive, Suite 3600  
Chicago, IL 60606-6383  
312.715.1010  
Fax 312.566.9729

The information presented on this website has been compiled from sources and documents believed to be reliable and represents the best professional judgment of the NRAEF, NRA Solutions, the Association, and/or such other individuals or entities, as applicable. The accuracy of the information presented, however, is not guaranteed, nor is any responsibility assumed or implied, by the NRAEF, NRA Solutions, the Association, and/or any other individual or entity, as applicable for any damage or loss resulting from inaccuracies or omissions.

Although this website includes links providing direct access to other websites, NRA Solutions takes no responsibility for the content or information contained on those other sites, and does not exert any editorial or other control over those other sites.

All downloadable files are distributed on an "as is" basis without warranties of any kind, express or implied, including, without limitation, warranties of title or implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose, and downloading and/or using the files is at the user's sole risk.
